<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DSGO on Javier&#39;s Data Site</title>
    <link>/categories/dsgo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DSGO on Javier&#39;s Data Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/dsgo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DataScienceGO 2018 (Part 2/2 - Tips &amp; Resources)</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-31-datasciencego-2018-part-2-of-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-31-datasciencego-2018-part-2-of-2/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few weeks to digest my experience at DataScienceGO 2018, definitely one for the books. I especially enjoyed making so many connections and absorbing (or rather, writing-a-million-miles-an-hour) so much knowledge over a short weekend. As promised, I wanted to share useful resources that I learned of at DSGO. Below I&amp;rsquo;m presenting my favorites, by presenter.
Send me a note here or on LinkedIn if you have any questions or check out my Resources page now updated with some of the items below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataScienceGO 2018 (Part 1/2 - Recap)</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-15-datasciencego-2018-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-15-datasciencego-2018-conference/</guid>
      <description>DataScienceGO 2018 was a blast! Kirill Eremenko, Hadelin de Ponteves, SuperDataScience, Formulatedby, and all the crew/staff put on a great conference&amp;hellip;. Career advice from business intelligence and data science executives, practical use cases for machine learning and artificial intelligence, data storytelling tips and visualization resources, LOTS of &amp;ldquo;secret sauce&amp;rdquo; from thought leaders, lots of networking (and lots of Pablos!)&amp;hellip; It will take me a week just to digest my notes but I will share my favorite insights and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>