<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scatter Podcast on Javier&#39;s Data Site</title>
    <link>/categories/scatter-podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scatter Podcast on Javier&#39;s Data Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/scatter-podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Podcast Episode 5 w/ Databricks</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-08-scatter-podcast-episode-005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-08-scatter-podcast-episode-005/</guid>
      <description>New episode of Scatter Podcast is online with Rafi Kurlansik of Databricks. Rafi has great perspective given his unique opportunities as a data scientist within tech sales and pre-sales teams. He also shares some great resources if you’re interested in learning Databricks, a cloud-based unified analytics platform. Happy Monday!
Other links: * Databricks * Databricks Community Edition * MLflow on Databricks
Scatter Podcast is available on SoundCloud, iTunes &amp;amp; Apple Podcasts, Spotify, TuneIn, Google Play Music, Stitcher Radio, Castbox, and Podcast Republic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Podcast Official Launch</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-31-scatter-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-31-scatter-podcast/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to announce that Scatter Podcast is finally live (available on most music and podcast streaming platforms)! The first four episodes include a podcast intro and three episodes with engaging guests from The Home Depot, Pacific Life, and NYC &amp;amp; Company.
I plan to release one episode weekly - Look out for upcoming interviews with data science reps from T-Mobile, Databricks, KPMG, Chegg, Technossus, Levi Strauss, Google, TensorIoT, and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Podcast Preview</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-02-04-scatter-podcast-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-02-04-scatter-podcast-preview/</guid>
      <description>Super excited with the interviews I&amp;rsquo;ve been recording recently for Scatter Podcast (LAUNCHING SOON)! There are so many great data science podcasts that I regularly enjoy, I&amp;rsquo;m just hoping to offer a slightly different angle. I want to explore and share what &amp;ldquo;data science&amp;rdquo; means at different companies, what day-to-day life is like within those teams, and better understand what experiences and skills certain companies value for potential candidates in their analytics, insights, and data science roles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>