<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business Analytics on Javier&#39;s Data Site</title>
    <link>/categories/business-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business Analytics on Javier&#39;s Data Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/business-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics Presentations at UC Irvine</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-12-analytics-presentations-at-uc-irvine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-12-analytics-presentations-at-uc-irvine/</guid>
      <description>For my University of California, Irvine, MSBA classmates&amp;hellip; I’ve been blown away by the presentations you’ve given the last few days and humbled by your aptitude for data analytics! Just one more week (of finals! 😅)&amp;hellip; we got this!
My team used Python to web-scrape Marvel Cinematic Universe movie rating and financial data since the release of Iron Man (2008). The goal was to predict the US Box Office revenues for Avengers: End Game given ratings, budget, and revenue patterns of all the recent Marvel movies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python for Business FREE In-Person Training</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-01-10-python-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-01-10-python-for-business/</guid>
      <description>Interested in an instructor led Python crash course? I&amp;rsquo;m a board member for UCI&amp;rsquo;s Merage Analytics Club and we&amp;rsquo;re hosting a 1.5 hour Python for Business training led by my classmate and extremely talented programmer and data storyteller, Samira Kumar Varadharajan.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be walking through Jupyter Notebook and providing an introduction to the following: 1. Basic Python libraries 2. Better visualizations in Python 3. Machine learning via Scikit-Learn
This event is open to all (students and non-students), is free for MSA members, and only costs 5 bucks for nonmembers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UC Irvine&#39;s MS in Business Analytics</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11-21-uc-irvine-ms-in-business-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11-21-uc-irvine-ms-in-business-analytics/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in data science, machine learning, and adding business value through data-driven decision making, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to chat about my experiences so far at the University of California, Irvine. The Paul Merage School of Business did a student profile on me about why I chose the MS in Business Analytics program. UCI placed my profile alongside an overview of the program&amp;rsquo;s curriculum and capstone projects (both of which were key factors for selecting UCI over other universities).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>