<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javier Orraca. Data Scientist.</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Javier Orraca. Data Scientist.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 01:18:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 26 w/ RStudio</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/episode-026/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 01:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/episode-026/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 026 of Scatter Podcast, I interviewed guest Jonathan Regenstein, Director of Financial Services at RStudio. Having spent several years at J.P. Morgan where he worked alongside quantitative analysts and researchers, Jonathan turned from Excel to R for more robust reporting, visualizations, and reproducibility of financial models. After joining RStudio, he continued to develop his R programming skills and eventually authored &amp;ldquo;Reproducible Finance with R - Code Flows and Shiny Apps for Portfolio Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Website with Blogdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-18-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-18-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pablo Barajas, a friend and recent graduate with me at UC Irvine, led a presentation on how to build a website using R, RStudio, and Blogdown. For anyone wanting to fairly easily build an online portfolio or blog that looks professional, I highly recommend Blogdown. I used this process to build this website, as did Pablo for his personal website, and I can help if you have any questions. Here&amp;rsquo;s the process in short: RStudio site build with Blogdown -&amp;gt; Commit to GitHub -&amp;gt; Apply Hugo theme -&amp;gt; Netlify for CI/CD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 Tips on Making Better Use of R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-11-r-markown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-11-r-markown/</guid>
      <description>If you use R but aren&amp;rsquo;t using R Markdown, you should be. It&amp;rsquo;s such a great way to make reports come to life. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it more in the last month than I have in the last year and can&amp;rsquo;t believe how much more interactive I&amp;rsquo;ve made my deliverables (and even my own data exploration). Really excited to see what new tricks I can learn from RStudio&amp;rsquo;s webinar on Friday, November 15!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 25 w/ Business Science</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/episode-025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 01:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/episode-025/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 025 of Scatter Podcast, I interviewed guest Matt Dancho, CEO and lead Data Science instructor at Business Science University. I&amp;rsquo;m currently enrolled in Matt&amp;rsquo;s R Shiny 102 course and have really enjoyed his training style full with sample code and video explanations on every module.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in developing your analytics and data science chops with the R programming language, Matt is offering a special 15% discount for his 4-course R machine learning bundle whe you enter discount code SCATTERPODCAST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Developer Expert Course</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-05-r-shiny-expert-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-05-r-shiny-expert-course/</guid>
      <description>I am super excited about Matt Dancho&amp;rsquo;s new R Shiny Developer course, especially since he&amp;rsquo;s the next guest on Scatter Podcast. He&amp;rsquo;s one of the best data science educators that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from and the deeper that I dive into my data science career, the more and more value I find from his Business Science courses, Learning Labs, his online tutorials (on the tidyverse, predictive analytics, data science best practices), his R packages&amp;hellip; The guy is a beast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 03:42:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Updated: October 2019 Note: Python online learning recommendations need updating. The Python books are still highly recommended.
Below are data science resources to point you in the right direction for learning more about data analytics, data science, and programming. I&amp;rsquo;ll update the list periodically as I learn of new resources and tools. R, Python, and SQL are programming languages used for data collection, data manipulation, data analytics, statistical analysis, web scraping, machine learning, and artificial intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 24 w/ Google &amp; IE</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/episode-024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 01:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/episode-024/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 024 of Scatter Podcast, I interviewed Christina Stathopoulos, Analytical Consultant at Google and Adjunct Professor at IE Business School in Madrid. Christina has a BS in Science, Technology, and Society from North Carolina State University and holds a MS in Business Analytics and Big Data from IE Business School in Madrid. Having spent seven years in Spain and traveling frequently for business, workshops, and leisure, Christina shares a unique, international perspective on the state of data science and the tech world in 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBC&#39;s Visual &amp; Data Journalism</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-10-22-bbc-visualization-journey-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-10-22-bbc-visualization-journey-with-r/</guid>
      <description>It pains me to share a Medium article of any kind these days because the bane of my existence is reaching my Medium article limit on the first day of the month (#EndRant). The BBC News data science and visualization team published this great overview on their lessons learned after using R for visualizations over the course of 1.5 years.
Great read, AND super neat to see the BBC team open-source their BBPLOT and R Cookbook to help streamline your visualization workflows, reduce manual repetition of code setup for a ggplot2 viz, and to educate you on better storytelling approaches with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information is Beautiful 2019 Awards</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-10-19-information-is-beautiful-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-10-19-information-is-beautiful-awards/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I had Will Chase on my podcast to talk about his work as a researcher and data visualization professional. Super exciting news for Will&amp;hellip; His visualizing earthquake risk project was shortlisted for the Information is Beautiful 2019 Awards (the Science &amp;amp; Technology category). Give it a look and if you like what you see, please vote for his amazing project!! Congrats Will!
Links:
 Vote for Will&amp;rsquo;s project on Kantar&amp;rsquo;s Information is Beautiful 2019 Awards Will&amp;rsquo;s (new!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering R Shiny (Book Preview)</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-10-15-mastering-r-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-10-15-mastering-r-shiny/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a blue moon when I log into Twitter, I&amp;rsquo;ll come across some gems that excite me&amp;hellip; Such was the case this morning when I learned that Hadley Wickham of RStudio is writing a book called &amp;ldquo;Mastering Shiny,&amp;rdquo; expected for publication in late 2020 by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in a free resource for learning how to develop R Shiny web apps, the first few chapters of &amp;ldquo;Mastering Shiny&amp;rdquo; are online (in development) full of code samples to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 23 w/ Blizzard</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/episode-023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 01:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/episode-023/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 023 of Scatter Podcast, I interviewed Hayden Balow, Organizational Development Analyst at Blizzard Entertainment. In the mid-1990&amp;rsquo;s, I was a fanatic of the Warcraft, Diablo, and Starcraft series so I really enjoyed hearing how Hayden&amp;rsquo;s team utilizes research, statistics, and people analytics to make the Blizzard workplace better for their employees. Hayden attended the University of Minnesota-Duluth for his Bachelor of Applied Science in Psychology, and he received his Masters in Industrial Organizational Psychology from Lamar University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSGO Conference, Day 1</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-10-08-dsgo-day-1-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-10-08-dsgo-day-1-recap/</guid>
      <description>Data Science GO (&amp;ldquo;DSGO&amp;rdquo;) was a huge success. It was great to reconnect with data science practitioners and leaders that I met at DSGO 2018, and to learn about the latest trends and how much the space has changed in just one year. I felt a lot of pride seeing UCI&amp;rsquo;s MS in Business Analytics (&amp;ldquo;MSBA&amp;rdquo;) program as the main educational sponsor for the event, and I also enjoyed seeing my old professor, Sanjeev Dewan, talk on the main stage about causal inference methods in data science (that&amp;rsquo;s him in the picture, above)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TensorFlow 2.0 for R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-10-07-tensorflow-2-for-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-10-07-tensorflow-2-for-r/</guid>
      <description>TensorFlow 2.0 is finally alpha-released. I use Python and R but tend to focus on R these days. So, what changes should R users be aware of? The RStudio team wrote a thorough post on the subject, providing a tour of the new r-tensorflow ecosystem, with code samples.
The good news? If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using TensorFlow within keras, like me, syntactically almost everything remains the same. You&amp;rsquo;ll notice very few differences, if any.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Earthquake Risk</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-10-02-visualizing-earthquake-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-10-02-visualizing-earthquake-risk/</guid>
      <description>On my most recent podcast episode, data visualization designer Will Chase covered one of his most ambitious projects yet, Visualizing Earthquake Risk, using R, Mapbox, and D3. Will is entirely self-taught and he created this interactive data viz after just two years of experience with R&amp;hellip; Incredible!
If you&amp;rsquo;re an R user or student, Will shares all of his code for this project (link below). Check out the podcast episode and Will&amp;rsquo;s website for more information, and if you&amp;rsquo;re active on Twitter, be sure to follow Will there (W_R_Chase).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 22 w/ UPenn</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/episode-022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/episode-022/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 022 of Scatter Podcast, I had an engaging interview with Will Chase, Data Scientist at the University of Pennsylvania. I stumbled upon one of Will&amp;rsquo;s interactive, web-based data visualizations (&amp;ldquo;Visualizing Risk: Remotely Triggered Earthquakes&amp;rdquo; - link below) and was fascinated by the way he leveraged the power of R, Mapbox, and D3 for this stunning data storytelling project.
Will has a BS in Microbiology and is almost entirely self-taught in the programming, data science, and advanced visualization space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UC Irvine at Data Science GO</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09-25-uci-at-dsgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09-25-uci-at-dsgo/</guid>
      <description>Data science students and managers exploring analytics for your organization&amp;hellip; The best data science conference is next weekend and only a few seats are left. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning about practical methods and technologies to help you derive robust, data-driven insights, you&amp;rsquo;ll walk away with SO much intel from the Data Science GO (&amp;ldquo;DSGO&amp;rdquo;) conference.
Last year, I convinced 7 of my UC Irvine (&amp;ldquo;UCI&amp;rdquo;) MSc in Business Analytics (&amp;ldquo;MSBA&amp;rdquo;) graduate cohort to attend DSGO with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Spreadsheets with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09-18-beyond-spreadsheets-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09-18-beyond-spreadsheets-with-r/</guid>
      <description>As a starting point for tackling data analysis problems, I often start from the perspective of &amp;ldquo;how would I have done this in Excel, if even possible?&amp;rdquo; This is what happens when you&amp;rsquo;ve spent the bulk of your career knee-deep in Excel and then you shift to more advanced data science tools like Python and R.
I love good reference books and one that I keep on my bookshelf is Beyond Spreadsheets with R, by Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 21 w/ Zeff.ai</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/episode-021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/episode-021/</guid>
      <description>For Episode 021 of Scatter Podcast, I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to have had the chance to interview Ben Taylor! Ben, the Co-Founder and Chief AI Officer at Zeff, is a wealth of knowledge about data science, artificial intelligence, and careers in these fields. I had a great time with him and we cover a lot including one of Ben&amp;rsquo;s recent, jaw-dropping side projects that is in development: A trained, AI-powered Call of Duty player that battles humans over Xbox Live!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker containers using Binder</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09-12-docker-container-using-binder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09-12-docker-container-using-binder/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent weeks slowly (and patiently) learning how to build and deploy Docker containers&amp;hellip; All was good, just dense for beginners. I was elated to find an easier approach to 1) building a Docker image with all the necessary packages / dependencies that you need, and 2) deploying an interactive web notebook (using a RStudio or Jupyter interface).
Some setup is involved, granted, the process is significantly streamlined with Binder. There is one main caveat here - Your data must be on a GitHub repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly &amp; Outlier Detection</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09-03-anomaly-and-outlier-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09-03-anomaly-and-outlier-detection/</guid>
      <description>Anomaly and outlier detection&amp;hellip; Neat, advanced stuff in this space that I finally got my hands dirty with in R. The anomalize package, created by Matt Dancho, helped me identify outliers and smooth out my forecasting model (backtesting also improved). I used anomalize in conjunction with Facebook&amp;rsquo;s prophet for a time-series projection. For R users out there: This package works beautifully with the tidyverse.
I&amp;rsquo;m continuously impressed by the stuff that Matt puts out including educational content, tutorials, webinars, and his package development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 20 w/ MaCher</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-09-02-scatter-podcast-episode-020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-09-02-scatter-podcast-episode-020/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 020 of Scatter Podcast, I had a lot of fun hosting industrial designer Ben Denzinger, Product Designer at MaCher. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a traditional data science episode but one focused on a topic that analytics and data science teams should become familiar with: Design Thinking. Design thinking is not a new concept, product designers like Ben have used it for decades, yet it is a framework that can be used in almost all aspects of business to justify your existing solution or to develop alternative solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSGO 2019 Conference</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08-29-data-science-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08-29-data-science-go/</guid>
      <description>The best data science conference is right around the corner! I attended Data Science GO in 2018 and loved it&amp;hellip; I met industry veterans, business managers, corporate data science leaders, and students wanting to make the most of predictive analytics and data science. Follow the link below to save 43% on DSGO19 today only!
Kirill Eremenko&amp;rsquo;s Super Data Science podcast was the inspiration for Scatter Podcast, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have pivoted my career into this direction had it not been for his insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students! Huge sale from Manning Publications</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08-24-manning-book-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08-24-manning-book-sale/</guid>
      <description>Analytics and data science students! Manning Publications Co. is having a killer sale at the moment (50% off purchases over $100). See the discount codes in the image that I posted. So many great physical books on their catalog, but this sale extends to their content in all formats&amp;hellip; Grab a group of friends and take advantage of these deals. Here are a few Manning books that I own and would highly recommend:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Thinking</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08-21-design-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08-21-design-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Design thinking is being talked about a lot more these days. It is an iterative, problem-solving approach that helps new solutions come to light that aren&amp;rsquo;t always apparent at first glance. Design thinking is not a new concept, designers have used it for years, and it can be used in all aspects of business to conceptualize alternative strategies or to justify your original solution.
Most recently, design thinking has been championed by leading data scientists (and non-technical professionals) given the benefits of applying a scientific method to solving business problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 19 w/ Amazon</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-08-19-scatter-podcast-episode-019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-08-19-scatter-podcast-episode-019/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 019 of Scatter Podcast, I discuss data science at Amazon with John Peach, Sr. Data Scientist. John has an extensive data science background ranging from academia, to early-stage startups, to large data drive organizations such as Amazon. His team helps to improve and expand the capabilities of Alexa Skills (third party applications).
John actively participates in his local data science community, he is one of the leaders of the Orange County R Users Group (&amp;ldquo;OCRUG&amp;rdquo;), and he frequently speaks at data science conferences around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 18 w/ Saatchi &amp; Saatchi</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-08-12-scatter-podcast-episode-018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-08-12-scatter-podcast-episode-018/</guid>
      <description>Lots of neat things happening at the intersection of media &amp;amp; entertainment, analytics, and operations. For Episode 018 of Scatter Podcast, I interviewed Leondra R. James, Manager, Analytics &amp;amp; Operations at Saatchi &amp;amp; Saatchi.
From violinist and music major to data scientist, Leondra has had a unique mix of academic and professional experiences that shaped her career in data. Saatchi &amp;amp; Saatchi is a global advertising agency operating in 76 countries and Leondra works in their Los Angeles office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tableau Chart Catalog</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08-06-tableau-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08-06-tableau-gallery/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been really quiet recently&amp;hellip; All is great, just busy with some client projects and building two websites for myself for the first time (both using R and this site included!). I wanted to share this awesome catalog of Tableau Software charts presented by Kevin Flerlage. Amazing stuff here and great reference to bookmark. Sometimes, all we need is a little creative inspiration to help us design stunning charts. Happy visualizing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 17 w/ ViralGains</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-29-scatter-podcast-episode-017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-29-scatter-podcast-episode-017/</guid>
      <description>For Episode 017 of Scatter Podcast, I interviewed Justin Fortier, Principal Data Scientist at ViralGains. Justin and I met at the Data Science GO conference in 2018 and I enjoyed getting to learn about his journey as a data scientist. ViralGains is a video advertising technology startup that helps publishers push video ad content to the most appropriate consumers. Given that ViralGains operates within the real-time bidding (&amp;ldquo;RTB&amp;rdquo;) domain, their ad bidding and classification algorithms need to transact and process within 100 milliseconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotly.py 4.0 - Offline Visualizations</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-25-plotly-offline-and-plotly-express/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-25-plotly-offline-and-plotly-express/</guid>
      <description>Python users: pip install plotly==4.0.0
Definitely excited to use the updated Plotly.py. This shift to offline-only is amazing. It &amp;ldquo;requires no internet connection, no account, no authentication tokens, and no payment of any kind.&amp;rdquo; Great stuff here, and now Plotly Express comes built in to make interactive plot making even easier&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;plotly.express is to plotly what seaborn is to matplotlib&amp;rdquo;
For you Jupyter and Colab fans, rendering Plotly figures to these notebooks (and other IDEs) should now feel a lot less clunky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Lessons Learned the Hard Way</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-23-linux-tips-learned-the-hard-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-23-linux-tips-learned-the-hard-way/</guid>
      <description>Here are a few tips, learned the hard way, for Linux beginners, data science students, or practitioners wanting to use Linux for machine learning and AI:
1) If you plan on dual-booting with Windows, there is not a one-size-fits-all solution. Setting up your Windows and BIOS settings to allow for disk partitions and Linux dual-boot can be manufacturer and/or Windows-version specific. I have a Lenovo ThinkPad and I am running pre-installed Windows 10 Professional&amp;hellip; If you have a similar system and looking to dual-boot, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to help with Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 16 w/ MeridianLink</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-22-scatter-podcast-episode-016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-22-scatter-podcast-episode-016/</guid>
      <description>For Episode 016 of Scatter Podcast, I had a great time interviewing Ben Lewis, Business Intelligence Analyst at MeridianLink. Ben and I met at a hackathon hosted by the Orange County R Users Group (&amp;ldquo;OCRUG&amp;rdquo;) and I was immediately impressed by his R skills. He has an Industrial Engineering and Operations Research background from the University of California, Berkeley, and as a BI Analyst at MeridianLink, he regularly programs in R for analytics, dashboards, and Shiny web-apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Container Tutorial for Beginners</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-19-docker-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-19-docker-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Many of the developers and data scientists that I follow on LinkedIn have had extensive exposure to Docker for building and deploying apps via containers&amp;hellip; I have not, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this for months and finally got around to researching where to start. I came across this IN-DEPTH(!!) and well-written Docker Tutorial for Beginners by Prakhar Srivastav.
Amazing stuff here, and exactly the kind of resource that I like to share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume Tip... Don&#39;t Lie!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-17-resume-tip-do-not-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-17-resume-tip-do-not-lie/</guid>
      <description>I came across this meme today and it cracked me up&amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s a big difference between lying on your resume and embellishing (I&amp;rsquo;ve written about this before, but even with embellishing, there is a line that you can easily cross). But folks&amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t lie about your experience on your resume. It&amp;rsquo;s not good for you or your employer (if they fall for your lies), and definitely not good for your reputation if you get into something way over your head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 15 w/ General Motors</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-15-scatter-podcast-episode-015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-15-scatter-podcast-episode-015/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 015 of Scatter Podcast, I had the pleasure of interviewing Meltem Ballan, Ph.D., Data Scientist and Architect at General Motors. Meltem&amp;rsquo;s deep analytical and data science expertise developed over her 20 years of experience in academia, consulting, and the corporate world. In fact, before &amp;ldquo;data science&amp;rdquo; became a catchphrase, Meltem was referred to as an algorithm developer.
At GM, Meltem&amp;rsquo;s team aims to enhance the driver experience where she applies neuroscience theory to analyze massive data sets via machine learning and artificial intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editable ggplot2 plots from R to PowerPoint</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-13-exporting-plots-from-r-to-powerpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-13-exporting-plots-from-r-to-powerpoint/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a super useful and easy approach, with sample code, for exporting R ggplot2 plots to PowerPoint as geometric shapes (vector objects). Using the officer R package, you&amp;rsquo;re able to edit the styling of your plots directly in PowerPoint to match your presentation theme or change to your liking. This also works on LibreOffice for Linux distributions.
Source:
 Blog Post: Exporting editable plots from R to Powerpoint by Bruno Rodrigues, Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R &#43; dplyr for Data Scientists</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-10-dplyr-for-data-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-10-dplyr-for-data-scientists/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve previously posted about the benefits of the dplyr package for data manipulation and performing if/else functions, but I wanted to share this R-bloggers post by Markus Berroth. The post includes base R vs dplyr sample code to demonstrate how dplyr can make life easier for data scientists. The Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) illustrations are also super helpful for understanding what&amp;rsquo;s happening with your R code.
These type of AST visuals are all over Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s Advanced R (Second Edition), and they&amp;rsquo;ve definitely helped me to better understand my R code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence for Social Good</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-09-ai-for-social-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-09-ai-for-social-good/</guid>
      <description>This is a great, 22-minute presentation by Neil Sahota at an AI conference. I met Sahota through UC Irvine, he recently taught my Technology &amp;amp; Analytics Consulting graduate course. In this video, Sahota discusses how AI can be used for social good and biodiversity. Professor Sahota is a beast&amp;hellip; In addition to recently publishing his first book on AI for business, he&amp;rsquo;s extremely active in the data science community and contributes through mentorship and consulting, he&amp;rsquo;s an IBM Master Inventor, he&amp;rsquo;s the United Nations AI subject matter expert, and co-founder of the AI for Good initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 14 w/ Fehr &amp; Peers</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-08-scatter-podcast-episode-014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-08-scatter-podcast-episode-014/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 014 of Scatter Podcast, I interview David Wasserman, AICP, Transportation Planner &amp;amp; Data Scientist at Fehr &amp;amp; Peers. Specializing in transportation planning and engineering services, Fehr &amp;amp; Peers is a consulting firm that has serviced public and private sectors since 1985. David has worked with them for four years at the intersection of data science, transportation and urban planning, and he takes us through a deep dive into some of the work that he&amp;rsquo;s done (providing career tips along the way!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to Handle Big Data Using Spark</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-05-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-05-spark/</guid>
      <description>Rahul Agarwal recently wrote an article for Towards Data Science that provides a great overview on the history of MapReduce, Spark, and using Python / PySpark for data engineering. I worked on a project recently with two people and we were shocked at how computationally efficient Spark was for our use case. We were able to load, read, manipulate, and explore over 30 GB of data in a Google Colab, GPU-enabled environment without reaching Google&amp;rsquo;s RAM limitation&amp;hellip; If you&amp;rsquo;ve used Colab, you know that you can eat through 12 GB of GPU RAM quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Finance &amp; Advanced R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-03-advanced-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-03-advanced-r/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m done with school but excited to continue learning! I picked up a copy of Jonathan Regenstein&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Reproducible Finance with R&amp;rdquo; and Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Advanced R&amp;rdquo; (2nd Edition, recently released). For my old co-workers in valuation, financial modeling, and corporate finance, I urge all of you to learn the R programming language. I assure you that you&amp;rsquo;ll still use Excel (often), but from a reproducibility perspective for your complex recurring analyses and forecasts, R is a better solution for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Synth &amp; Sequencing Basics</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-07-02-ableton-live-learning-synths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-07-02-ableton-live-learning-synths/</guid>
      <description>June was a wild but exciting month&amp;hellip; I finished some major projects for school, graduated, moved, and most recently went abroad on vacation to disconnect. Definitely a nice recharge for the soul! Some neat things are on the horizon and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to release my next wave of Scatter Podcast episodes starting on July 8.
I recently discovered an amazing online learning platform to learn about synthesizers and I had to share it&amp;hellip; This might not be your cup of tea but if you like music, you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCI News with Scatter Podcast</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-14-scatter-podcast-in-the-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-14-scatter-podcast-in-the-news/</guid>
      <description>Several months back, I launched Scatter Podcast to share insights about all things &amp;ldquo;data science&amp;rdquo; and career tips from leaders in the space. On my podcast, I interview practitioners to demystify what it means to be a data scientist since it has many shapes and forms in business intelligence, advanced analytics, programming, and data storytelling.
The UCI Paul Merage School of Business recently interviewed me and published an article about my work with Scatter Podcast (link below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce Stock Price Prediction via R &#43; Tableau</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-13-salesforce-prediction-via-tableau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-13-salesforce-prediction-via-tableau/</guid>
      <description>Where will Salesforce stock (CRM) be at the end of 2019? $178.40! I used R to produce a multi-variate time series model and Tableau to visualize historical CRM stock prices (grey line) vs my model (blue line), including my Dec 2019 prediction (red dot). The model was built in February using historical stock price data from 2004 to 2018. Play around with the Tableau viz (link below)!
Independent Variables: U.S. consumer sentiment index (published by the University of Michigan) GDP CRM historical stock prices Other tech stocks (IBM, Oracle, SAP) Month (as categorical, for seasonality)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And voila! Interactive Dashboards for Jupyter</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-11-voila/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-11-voila/</guid>
      <description>Super excited about voila! Creating interactive web dashboards with Jupyter Notebooks via R or Python is getting easier, faster, and hopefully with more control.
Plotly API calls have been manageable for me through Jupyter Notebooks, but I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly seem some limitations using the free Plotly account, Plotly Offline, or similar offline packages.
Either way, Project Jupyter&amp;rsquo;s developments with JupyterLab, JupyterHub, and QuantStack&amp;rsquo;s voila are about to make programming collaboration and visualizations a lot more fun!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Podcast Break &amp; UCI&#39;s MSBA Class</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-09-scatter-podcast-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-09-scatter-podcast-break/</guid>
      <description>Scatter Podcast will be on a short hiatus this week and next, but returning in two weeks with fresh new content from data scientists in consulting, transportation planning, banking, automobile manufacturing, and more! School got in the way wrapping up massive projects, reports, and final exams.
The last year has flown by and I&amp;rsquo;m graduating with a MS in Business Analytics from University of California, Irvine. This is a snapshot of my MSBA class&amp;hellip; Smart, kind, and funny people from all over the world and now I get to call them friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-07-time-series-analysis-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-07-time-series-analysis-with-r/</guid>
      <description>I just got Hands-On Time Series Analysis with R, by Rami Krispin, and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to crack it open! I have a knack for time-series analyses given most of the financial data and modeling I previously worked with was time-series based. Had I known the full potential of advanced time-series forecasting techniques, I would have implemented some of these techniques yesterday! But as the saying goes, and it&amp;rsquo;s so cliche, but true, &amp;ldquo;you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Deep Learning GPU Server</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-06-05-building-a-deep-learning-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-06-05-building-a-deep-learning-server/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Google Cloud Platform (GCP) can be phenomenal for processing deep learning models in the cloud, but there&amp;rsquo;s a catch - especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a student or enthusiast with no corporate account access - These cloud tools get expensive! For $1-3 per hour, you can cloud compute using AWS or GCP&amp;hellip; Not bad! But if you want extended access to your cloud instances, or 24&amp;frasl;7 access as I&amp;rsquo;d like to have, cloud solutions become cost prohibitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 13 w/ Method Data Science</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-06-03-scatter-podcast-episode-013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-06-03-scatter-podcast-episode-013/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 013 of Scatter Podcast, I had a great time interviewing Beau Walker, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of Method Data Science. Beau is actively involved in the data science community, is a passionate R and Python educator, and it was a pleasure to glean some career insights from him. Method is on a mission to inspire and train the next generation of data scientists, and they&amp;rsquo;re accomplishing this by managing small teams of Resident Data Scientists working on real-world data engagements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux &amp; Ubuntu Help Request</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05-30-linux-help-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05-30-linux-help-request/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking of giving Ubuntu a shot&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m currently using Windows 10 (and all is good, honestly). Granted, the more I dive into analytics and data science research (and especially GPU processing), the more benefit I see from driving my data management and machine learning through a Linux command prompt.
Backstory: I&amp;rsquo;ve been researching external GPU rigs and I am considering building one. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use it for gaming but for faster ML (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving R Data Objects to File for Quick Loading</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05-29-saving-r-data-objects-to-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05-29-saving-r-data-objects-to-file/</guid>
      <description>R users! Are you spending too much time reading large data sets, wrangling, then waiting to convert your data frames to matrices or arrays (and if you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you might be doing a lot of this locally)&amp;hellip; All of the sudden, you&amp;rsquo;ve got 25-50 GB (or more) worth of vector objects sitting in your environment and it&amp;rsquo;s taken 10-15 minutes to even get to this point where you can begin modeling&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 12 w/ TBWA-Chiat-Day</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-27-scatter-podcast-episode-012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-27-scatter-podcast-episode-012/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 012 of Scatter Podcast, I interview Matt Segal, Data Director at TBWA/Chiat/Day, a global creative advertising agency. Chiat/Day gained global notoriety with their &amp;ldquo;1984&amp;rdquo; ad campaign for Apple introducing the Macintosh computer. Their forward-thinking and disruptive style make for a unique place to work as a data strategist, and Matt discusses the benefits of data careers at advertising agencies. Matt shares recent project examples his data team has been involved with, he discusses tools regularly used for social listening and web analytics, and he shares solid resources for those of you interested in this space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Delimited File Read Times in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05-22-benchmarking-r-read-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05-22-benchmarking-r-read-methods/</guid>
      <description>I have been running code for a client project and each comma separated (csv) file is 300MB with 400,000+ records. Base R simply wasn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it for me and I was wasting too much time staring at my local system waiting for my files to be read.
I found the microbenchmark package and started exploring faster file read methods relative to base R. I discovered Tidyverse&amp;rsquo;s readr and vroom packages, and while I had used the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 11 w/ CBRE</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-20-scatter-podcast-episode-011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-20-scatter-podcast-episode-011/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 011 of Scatter Podcast, I interview Vince Giovannini, Data Scientist at CBRE, a commercial real estate investment company that also offers a wide range of real estate consulting services. Vince works in the Labor Analytics team at CBRE and shares great insights about the labor products he has worked on and how labor is connected to real estate economics. Vince shares several project examples that he&amp;rsquo;s been a part of at CBRE and it was great getting to hear how his firm uses data science to derive deeper insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Model at OC R Users Group 2019 Hackathon</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05-19-ocrug-hackathon-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05-19-ocrug-hackathon-2019/</guid>
      <description>I attended my first hackathon today and my team, save the worRld, won best model! Greg Faletto, Shruhi Desai, Sam Park, Faizan Haque - I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have asked for a better team, congrats! To the OC R Users Group team, John Peach and the Amazon EC2 resources that he provided, to all the volunteers, and to UC Irvine&amp;rsquo;s Paul Merage School of Business for hosting, thanks for putting on an amazing event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ray Kurzweil Explains AI and Future Intelligence</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05-17-artificial-intelligence-with-ray-kurzweil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05-17-artificial-intelligence-with-ray-kurzweil/</guid>
      <description>The YouTube link below is of Ray Kurzweil speaking at an MIT deep learning course (MIT Professor Lex Fridman&amp;rsquo;s artificial general intelligence course). Kurzwiel is a futurist and Google Director of Engineering. The way in which Kurzweil explains how humans learn and think (e.g., sequences of sequences in the neocortex), and how his brain research provided hints at how to build better and &amp;ldquo;deeper&amp;rdquo; neural networks&amp;hellip; Grab yourself a bag of popcorn and watch this 50 minute video, just amazing stuff here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did Harvard Get Marketing Analytics Wrong?&#39;</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05-15-analytics-alone-are-not-a-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05-15-analytics-alone-are-not-a-solution/</guid>
      <description>In May 2018, Harvard Business Review published a report (links below) titled &amp;ldquo;Why Marketing Analytics Hasn&amp;rsquo;t Lived Up to Its Promise.&amp;rdquo; My most recent Scatter Podcast guest, Ryan Anderson, wrote a critique of the HBR article that helps frame the conversation in another light: marketing analytics ALONE is not the solution.
We talked about the HBR piece and Ryan&amp;rsquo;s response on this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast release, but being that Ryan has made a career in strategic marketing and web analytics, I&amp;rsquo;d definitely recommend you read both of these articles if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in this line of work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 10 w/ FortyFour</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-13-scatter-podcast-episode-010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-13-scatter-podcast-episode-010/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 010 of Scatter Podcast, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to host guest Ryan Anderson, Director of Performance Marketing &amp;amp; Analytics at FortyFour. FortyFour is an independent digital agency based in Atlanta, GA, and Ryan leads their analytics team. Ryan, a Georgia Institute of Technology engineering and MBA alum, was a driving force for me diving into analytics and data science (thank you!).
Ryan has been a great sounding board the past couple of years and he&amp;rsquo;s a wealth of knowledge on analytics and digital strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revenue Predictions for Avengers Endgame</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05-10-avengers-endgame-box-office-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05-10-avengers-endgame-box-office-prediction/</guid>
      <description>In mid-March, I worked with a team of UC Irvine students to analyze the Marvel Cinematic Universe and predict US box office revenues for Avengers: Endgame. We estimated US box office revenues to be $639 million and as of today, domestic box office revenues are $645 million!
To my UC Irvine teammates (Ahnni, Daria, Joel, Xiaoting)&amp;hellip; Great job! At the time that we developed our predictions, Captain Marvel had only been in theaters for one week&amp;hellip; I just updated our models and our new domestic box office prediction for Endgame is $670 million.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 9 w/ RealBlocks</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-06-scatter-podcast-episode-009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-06-scatter-podcast-episode-009/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 009 of Scatter Podcast, I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to release my interview with Perrin Quarshie, CEO &amp;amp; Founder of RealBlocks. For those of you interested in real estate, technology, investing, blockchain&amp;hellip; This episode is for you!
Built upon the Ethereum blockchain, RealBlocks allows accredited investors to buy into private equity real estate funds through the purchase of digital assets. RealBlocks went through #Techstars NYC&amp;rsquo;s program (one of the top startup accelerators) and recently raised $3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 8 w/ Chegg</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-29-scatter-podcast-episode-008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-29-scatter-podcast-episode-008/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 008 of Scatter Podcast, I interview guest Taranveer Singh and discuss his work as a Data Scientist at Chegg. Through natural language processing (&amp;ldquo;NLP&amp;rdquo;) and data science, Taran&amp;rsquo;s team provides Chegg customers with a better user experience, ensuring the customer voice is heard. Chegg operates fast and smart, and data science enables the business to quickly research and deploy product features that are most desired by their community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version Control w/ Git &amp; GitHub</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-27-version-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-27-version-control/</guid>
      <description>Git, GitHub, and distributed version control can make your statistical and data science workflows so much cleaner, more organized, and perfect for collaborative projects. This is a topic that I&amp;rsquo;m just now researching and can&amp;rsquo;t believe that I waited this long to do.
In finance, I was accustomed to saving numerous files per day (adding the date and version to the end of the model filename). Git and GitHub have a learning curve and require effort - I&amp;rsquo;m learning this now and can attest to you needing patience - But, the beauty of this data management process is that instead of saving one file only, you &amp;ldquo;commit&amp;rdquo; or save a multi-file snapshot of your entire project to the cloud!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 7 w/ NeoGenomics Laboratories</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-22-scatter-podcast-episode-007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-22-scatter-podcast-episode-007/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 007 of Scatter Podcast, I interview guest Nicholas Stavrou and discuss his work as an Associate Scientist in Computational Biology at NeoGenomics Laboratories, a cancer diagnostic and pharma research company. Neo is advancing precision medication and Nicholas and I had an engaging talk about cancer cell classification, neural networks and AI models for cancer research, and how Nicholas developed his skills to land his role at Neo. Nicholas graduated from USC in 2017 and he shares some great tips and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Podcast on Forbes</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-18-forbes-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-18-forbes-article/</guid>
      <description>I had the privilege of recently interviewing data rockstar Alyssa Columbus, Data Scientist at Pacific Life and NASA Datanaut. Forbes interviewed her for a piece on How to Get Your Data Scientist Career Started and she was kind enough to mention Scatter Podcast as a resource for students to keep current on analytics and data science concepts. Great article and especially beneficial for early career data science job seekers.
Source: How to Get Your Data Scientist Career Started</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 6 w/ T-Mobile</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-15-scatter-podcast-episode-006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-15-scatter-podcast-episode-006/</guid>
      <description>For the sixth episode of Scatter Podcast, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to introduce Juan Pablo Murillo, Data Scientist at T-Mobile at their U.S. headquarters in Bellevue, WA (greater Seattle area). Mathematics instructor turned data scientist, Juan Pablo is in customer analytics and works with engineering and analytics teams to improve the T-Mobile and MetroPCS customer experience. He has been a solid data science mentor for me over the last few months, reviewing, rating, and critiquing some of my R scripts and insights that I derived&amp;hellip; Sharp guy and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share his data analytics passion with others!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Personalized Requests on Mobile App</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-09-linkedin-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-09-linkedin-tips/</guid>
      <description>Personalized LinkedIn requests CAN be sent through the mobile app&amp;hellip; I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize this until today, but the key is to avoid hitting Connect when youre shown a list of recommended contacts (this will send out a boilerplate request message). Instead, navigate to the contacts LinkedIn profile and from there, you have access to personalize your request note! Thanks to Kate Strachnyi for her live stream today and her candid advice is always appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 5 w/ Databricks</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-08-scatter-podcast-episode-005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-08-scatter-podcast-episode-005/</guid>
      <description>New episode of Scatter Podcast is online with Rafi Kurlansik of Databricks. Rafi has great perspective given his unique opportunities as a data scientist within tech sales and pre-sales teams. He also shares some great resources if youre interested in learning Databricks, a cloud-based unified analytics platform. Happy Monday!
Other links: Databricks Databricks Community Edition MLflow on Databricks
Scatter Podcast is available on SoundCloud, iTunes &amp;amp; Apple Podcasts, Spotify, TuneIn, Google Play Music, Stitcher Radio, Castbox, and Podcast Republic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dplyr&#39;s if_else vs base R&#39;s ifelse</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-03-dplyr-for-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-03-dplyr-for-r/</guid>
      <description>When working with data sets of significant size, I&amp;rsquo;m always on the lookout for more efficient code (not necessarily fewer lines of code, but code that processes data faster and more effectively). Recently, I was getting antsy waiting for a simple if/else statement to run via R (I was working with a large GB-sized file on my personal computer). While waiting, I researched alternative approaches for performance improvement and found that dplyr, part of R&amp;rsquo;s Tidyverse and one of my favorite packages for data manipulation, has a vectorized if function perfect for the occasion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official Launch w/ Episodes 1-4</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-03-31-scatter-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-03-31-scatter-podcast/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to announce that Scatter Podcast is finally live (available on most music and podcast streaming platforms)! The first four episodes include a podcast intro and three episodes with engaging guests from The Home Depot, Pacific Life, and NYC &amp;amp; Company.
I plan to release one episode weekly - Look out for upcoming interviews with data science reps from T-Mobile, Databricks, KPMG, Chegg, Technossus, Levi Strauss, Google, TensorIoT, and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Podcast Official Launch</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-31-scatter-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-31-scatter-podcast/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to announce that Scatter Podcast is finally live (available on most music and podcast streaming platforms)! The first four episodes include a podcast intro and three episodes with engaging guests from The Home Depot, Pacific Life, and NYC &amp;amp; Company.
I plan to release one episode weekly - Look out for upcoming interviews with data science reps from T-Mobile, Databricks, KPMG, Chegg, Technossus, Levi Strauss, Google, TensorIoT, and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost PC Performance with ThrottleStop</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-17-throttlestop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-17-throttlestop/</guid>
      <description>For Windows Users Wanting More Speed &amp;amp; Performance I&amp;rsquo;ve been puzzled as to why I felt a significant lag on my top-of-the-line laptop (especially prevalent with MS Excel - if you&amp;rsquo;re a power user, you&amp;rsquo;d have noticed immediately). Turns out, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; for my system to throttle the CPU at 1.9 GHz. Using ThrottleStop (free), I removed CPU throttling for speed gains and undervolted the CPU/cache/GPU for temperature control. I&amp;rsquo;m running stable at ~3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Madness Prediction Competition</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-13-march-madness-prediction-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-13-march-madness-prediction-competition/</guid>
      <description>The UCI Merage Analytics Association is hosting a March Madness prediction competition event on April 4th, come join us! Everybody is invited and we&amp;rsquo;ll be giving prizes to the best forecasters and bracket-pickers. Scan one (or both) of the QR codes in the flyer below or let me know if you have any questions. Hope to see you there!
Source: March Madness Event at UCI&amp;rsquo;s Paul Merage School of Business</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics Presentations at UC Irvine</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-12-analytics-presentations-at-uc-irvine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-12-analytics-presentations-at-uc-irvine/</guid>
      <description>For my University of California, Irvine, MSBA classmates&amp;hellip; Ive been blown away by the presentations youve given the last few days and humbled by your aptitude for data analytics! Just one more week (of finals! )&amp;hellip; we got this!
My team used Python to web-scrape Marvel Cinematic Universe movie rating and financial data since the release of Iron Man (2008). The goal was to predict the US Box Office revenues for Avengers: End Game given ratings, budget, and revenue patterns of all the recent Marvel movies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter Notebook via Google Colab</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-06-google-colab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-06-google-colab/</guid>
      <description>I only started learning Python in January but regularly use Jupyter Notebooks for all of my R-based projects. Last week, I discovered Google Colab&amp;hellip; After spending 24-32 hours on it, I might be in love!
Colab is free, Google cloud-based Jupyter notebook environment for team collaboration. No installs required. Just send your teammates a URL and you&amp;rsquo;re set! Give it a shot with uploading your own Jupyter ipynb files (or see link below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robots and Modern Art Installations</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-02-robots-and-modern-art-installations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-02-robots-and-modern-art-installations/</guid>
      <description>If youre based in SoCal, I highly recommend a visit to the Telestron installation (Feb 23 - March 28). This is an immersive, futuristic light show put on by VTProDesign and GMUNK. I love the intersection of art+technology and these robots do not disappoint!
A pair of robot arms project light patterns onto each other and all surfaces of the room during a seven-minute show.
Source: Telestron</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Data by Tableau</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-02-21-ask-data-by-tableau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-02-21-ask-data-by-tableau/</guid>
      <description>Tableau&amp;rsquo;s latest upgrade has a native natural language processing capability called Ask Data - Ask it a question in plain English (&amp;ldquo;What is the profit over time, by business line?&amp;rdquo;) and Tableau &amp;ldquo;determines the most appropriate visualization to satisfy the users intent.&amp;rdquo; Super neat, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to give the upgrade a spin!
On the surface, Ask Data seems gimmicky&amp;hellip; But as a starting point for visualizations, or for near-instant data investigation during a meeting, this is an awesome feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI and Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-02-13-ai-and-gans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-02-13-ai-and-gans/</guid>
      <description>I saw Ben Taylor present a few months back and was blown away. He&amp;rsquo;s continuously researching and educating himself, pushing the limits of deep learning, and he&amp;rsquo;s an advocate of side projects as a vehicle for growth (as am I!). Ben is super passionate about data science, harnessing computational power from GPU/CUDA systems, and his work with generative adversarial networks (GANs) is next level&amp;hellip;
The image above is an AI-produced synthetic face made possible through GANs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Podcast Preview</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-02-04-scatter-podcast-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-02-04-scatter-podcast-preview/</guid>
      <description>Super excited with the interviews I&amp;rsquo;ve been recording recently for Scatter Podcast (LAUNCHING SOON)! There are so many great data science podcasts that I regularly enjoy, I&amp;rsquo;m just hoping to offer a slightly different angle. I want to explore and share what &amp;ldquo;data science&amp;rdquo; means at different companies, what day-to-day life is like within those teams, and better understand what experiences and skills certain companies value for potential candidates in their analytics, insights, and data science roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Bowl Predictive Modeling Event</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-01-29-analytics-speaking-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-01-29-analytics-speaking-event/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago, I knew nothing about the NFL (despite my passion for ftbol!). I teamed up with my classmate and knowledgeable NFL fan, Kaitlyn Drake, and developed a model and game simulation via R to predict the Super Bowl winner and final scores. We predicted the Rams winning 15-14 itll be a close game. We relied on Poisson regression, game simulation, and C4.5 / J48 decision tree to derive our results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python FREE In-Person Training</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-01-10-python-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-01-10-python-for-business/</guid>
      <description>Interested in an instructor led Python crash course? I&amp;rsquo;m a board member for UCI&amp;rsquo;s Merage Analytics Club and we&amp;rsquo;re hosting a 1.5 hour Python for Business training led by my classmate and extremely talented programmer and data storyteller, Samira Kumar Varadharajan.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be walking through Jupyter Notebook and providing an introduction to the following: 1. Basic Python libraries 2. Better visualizations in Python 3. Machine learning via Scikit-Learn
This event is open to all (students and non-students), is free for MSA members, and only costs 5 bucks for nonmembers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Book Recommendations on Analytics &amp; Data Science</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-12-28-new-book-recommendations-for-analytics-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-12-28-new-book-recommendations-for-analytics-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Back to school, back to reading! Looking forward to these reads&amp;hellip; Im finding Naomi Ceders The Quick Python Book really helpful for learning Python 3&amp;hellip; definitely a learn-by-doing style that I like. Links to these books below:
Amazon Book Links: * The Quick Python Book * Superforecasting: The Art and Science of Prediction * Feature Engineering for Machine Learning * AMPL: A Modeling Language for Mathematical Programming * The Signal and The Noise * Python for Data Analysis * Applied Predictive Analytics * Learning Tableau 10 * Data Smart: Using Data Science to Transform Information into Insight</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Tips for Students &amp; Job Seekers</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11-27-interview-tips-for-students-job-seekers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11-27-interview-tips-for-students-job-seekers/</guid>
      <description>I joined LinkedIn&amp;rsquo;s Career Advice beta program and have been providing career and interview tips to students and professionals wanting a career change since 2017. Since several students have found my feedback helpful, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll welcome this unsolicited feedback. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m back in graduate school, it&amp;rsquo;s also a nice reminder for myself as we approach &amp;ldquo;interview season.&amp;rdquo; For some context, I&amp;rsquo;ve never had HR or Recruiter titles, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to have had many opportunities to interview college students and experienced professionals at EY, PG&amp;amp;E, and KPMG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UC Irvine&#39;s MS in Business Analytics</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11-21-uc-irvine-ms-in-business-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11-21-uc-irvine-ms-in-business-analytics/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in data science, machine learning, and adding business value through data-driven decision making, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to chat about my experiences so far at the University of California, Irvine. The Paul Merage School of Business did a student profile on me about why I chose the MS in Business Analytics program. UCI placed my profile alongside an overview of the program&amp;rsquo;s curriculum and capstone projects (both of which were key factors for selecting UCI over other universities).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wes Anderson Color Palettes for R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11-08-wes-anderson-movie-color-palettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11-08-wes-anderson-movie-color-palettes/</guid>
      <description>Are you a Wes Anderson fan and regular R user? If you want a color scheme makeover for your R visualizations, check out this fun Wes Anderson color palette package by Karthik Ram. Great stuff&amp;hellip; I just tried out The Grand Budapest Hotel palette for a correlation matrix (see above)!
Props to my classmate Kaitlyn Drake for finding this gem!
Source: Karthik&amp;rsquo;s Wes Anderson project (on GitHub)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Visualizations via R &#43; iGraph</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11-06-network-visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11-06-network-visualizations/</guid>
      <description>Network visualizations can be useful for understanding entity and large data interdependencies. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using R and the iGraph package to explore network analysis and found this tutorial to be EXCELLENT by Katherine Ognyanova. It takes a lot of time to build these network graphs and more time to interpret, but definitely rewarding when it provides insights you may have otherwise overlooked. The screenshot above is a network diagram that I made to represent Amazon product copurchases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataScienceGO 2018 (Part 2/2 - Tips &amp; Resources)</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-31-datasciencego-2018-part-2-of-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-31-datasciencego-2018-part-2-of-2/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few weeks to digest my experience at DataScienceGO 2018, definitely one for the books. I especially enjoyed making so many connections and absorbing (or rather, writing-a-million-miles-an-hour) so much knowledge over a short weekend. As promised, I wanted to share useful resources that I learned of at DSGO. Below I&amp;rsquo;m presenting my favorites, by presenter.
Send me a note here or on LinkedIn if you have any questions or check out my Resources page now updated with some of the items below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Machine Learning by Hand</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-26-really-learning-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-26-really-learning-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning via R, Python, (enter your tool of choice here)&amp;hellip; Not bad. But doing machine learning by hand, wow&amp;hellip; This is a true study of patience!
For a school assignment, we had to deconstruct a supervised machine learning model (Naive Bayes) using one data set for training and another for testing, all by hand. This was definitely rewarding being able to understand the depth of conditional probabilities in this classifier model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataScienceGO 2018 (Part 1/2 - Recap)</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-15-datasciencego-2018-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-15-datasciencego-2018-conference/</guid>
      <description>DataScienceGO 2018 was a blast! Kirill Eremenko, Hadelin de Ponteves, SuperDataScience, Formulatedby, and all the crew/staff put on a great conference&amp;hellip;. Career advice from business intelligence and data science executives, practical use cases for machine learning and artificial intelligence, data storytelling tips and visualization resources, LOTS of &amp;ldquo;secret sauce&amp;rdquo; from thought leaders, lots of networking (and lots of Pablos!)&amp;hellip; It will take me a week just to digest my notes but I will share my favorite insights and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Music Production</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-08-machine-learning-for-music-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-08-machine-learning-for-music-production/</guid>
      <description>If you know me personally, you likely know I enjoy playing with analog / digital synthesizers and experimental music production. I love seeing my interests cross&amp;hellip; FactorSynth, a new virtual musical tool and Ableton Live plug-in, uses machine learning to decompose your audio clips into elements. These musical elements can then be modified and recombined in various ways (in real-time). Check out this demo reel (my words don&amp;rsquo;t do this new device justice)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Azure&#39;s AI Capabilities</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-01-microsoft-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-01-microsoft-azure/</guid>
      <description>Building and training ML models takes a ton of time. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Azure can now automate several steps in your AI development process including &amp;ldquo;data transformation, model selection and hyperparameter tuning.&amp;rdquo; Really impressed that Azure is making this tech more accessible and easier to use. If you have hands-on work experience with Azure and don&amp;rsquo;t mind me asking you some questions, please message me, thanks!
Source: Microsoft Announcement: Automated AI via Azure</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-09-23-unsupervised-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-09-23-unsupervised-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>First quarter of grad school is finally over! Now with some free time, I finally learned Git (for BASH emulation), set up a GitHub account, and looking forward to collaborating on analytics projects. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in R or machine learning, one of my projects is a basic ML exercise that relies on the k-means algorithm for clustering.
Source: Unsupervised Machine Learning via k-means Algorithm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitbit&#39;s 150 Billion Hours of Heart Data</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-09-18-fitbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-09-18-fitbit/</guid>
      <description>Fitbit has collected over 150 billion hours of heart data&amp;hellip; a modern-day digital gold mine. David Pogue, reporting for Yahoo Finance, highlights data insights and stresses the importance of heart health!
Source: Yahoo! Finance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Salon (Los Angeles)</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-09-10-datasciencesalon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-09-10-datasciencesalon/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the Los Angeles or Orange County areas and interested in learning how to apply machine learning and artificial intelligence to media and entertainment, tickets are still available for Data Science Salon LA. Definitely excited about this one.
Event Details
Tickets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips From a Data Science Consultant</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-09-06-tim-lafferty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-09-06-tim-lafferty/</guid>
      <description>The data science community is super welcoming&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s been great connecting with professionals all over the world, meeting other beginners and helping each other out, sharing best practices and educational resources. I was excited to recently hear an interview with Tim Lafferty (Georgia Tech alum!) on the Super Data Science Podcast discussing life as a data science consultant. Really practical tips here (even bought Kirill&amp;rsquo;s book, Confident Data Skills after the listen!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix&#39;s Machine Learning Infrastructure</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-08-28-netflix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-08-28-netflix/</guid>
      <description>Netflix uses R and Python for machine learning and predictive modeling to support content recommendations and FAST delivery of content. On the We Are Netflix podcast series, Netflix has done an amazing job interviewing their data scientists and explaining how machine learning is enhancing the Netflix experience.
Source: WeAreNetflix on YouTube</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning R with swirl</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-08-20-learning-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-08-20-learning-r/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel&amp;rsquo;s pivot tables and Google Maps&amp;hellip; Obvious differences here, but both are driven by split-apply-combine methodologies that visualize data sets. If you want to learn how to make a pivot table &amp;ldquo;from scratch,&amp;rdquo; or enhance your analytics capabilities beyond Excel, learn R (or Python) as a starting point. R is an analytics and graphics programming language that is free, fun, and an interactive way to learn the R basics is via swirl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fake News &amp; Social Media</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-08-10-fake-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-08-10-fake-news/</guid>
      <description>The dissemination of fake news on social media is widespread, often fueled by bots and reinforced through user sharing. On the most recent episode of the Data Skeptic, host Kyle Polich interviews Filippo Menczer to discuss how bots influence the spread of fake news. For anyone interested in data analytics, this is a great listen and the link below also references several tools for studying the spread of information on social media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact &#43; social</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:42:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email &amp;amp; Phone Personal Email: orraca.javier@gmail.com Scatter Podcast: scatter.podcast@gmail.com Phone: +1-714-794-5668
Social Media LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/orraca/ Tableau Public: https://public.tableau.com/profile/javier.orraca Scatter Podcast on SoundCloud: https://soundcloud.com/scatterpodcast GitHub: https://github.com/JavOrraca Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/iwantmorejavier/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>professional resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:42:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging over 10 years of analysis, modeling, financial strategy, and project management experiences, I am seeking opportunities that will allow me to apply business analytics and machine learning for predictive modeling, business strategy, and data-driven insights. I am a creative problem solver driving value through advanced analytics and reproducible reporting.
Work Experiences Scatter Analytics, Irvine, CA Founder &amp;amp; Data Scientist (Jan 2019  Present)
 Scatter Analytics is a collective of data scientists and seasoned corporate professionals that provide consulting services to small and mid-sized businesses through machine learning, advanced visualizations, and AI solutions Analyzed survey response data to measure a fast-food chains brand equity against its competitors over five variables (loyalty, relevance, familiarity, uniqueness, popularity) and customer demographics (age, region, gender, income) Produced descriptive statistics to understand customer profiles of online vs offline banking users, developed a predictive multi-variate regression model for a local bank, predicted the likelihood of each offline user becoming an online banking user, and presented key insights and visualizations to leadership Utilized Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Prophet auto-regressing machine learning algorithm to produce product-level forecasting models, identifying outliers and seaonality trends, while visualizing results and anomalies in R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>who is javier?</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:42:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Javier Orraca and I drive business value for corporations and privately held businesses through data, predictive modeling, and empowering stakeholders with robust decision analytics.
Background My career includes over a decade of consulting, data analysis, and fixed asset valuation modeling for Ernst &amp;amp; Young (EY), Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric (PG&amp;amp;E), and KPMG. My work supported M&amp;amp;A financial reporting requirements and strategic finance initiatives. I had a vision of providing more value to business organizations than what my M&amp;amp;A and valuation work allowed for, so I began to explore and learn how to apply regressions and machine learning for advanced, data-driven decision making.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>