<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rstats on Javier&#39;s Data Site</title>
    <link>/categories/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rstats on Javier&#39;s Data Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>dplyr&#39;s if_else vs base R&#39;s ifelse</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-03-dplyr-for-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-03-dplyr-for-r/</guid>
      <description>When working with data sets of significant size, I&amp;rsquo;m always on the lookout for more efficient code (not necessarily fewer lines of code, but code that processes data faster and more effectively). Recently, I was getting antsy waiting for a simple if/else statement to run via R (I was working with a large GB-sized file on my personal computer). While waiting, I researched alternative approaches for performance improvement and found that dplyr, part of R&amp;rsquo;s Tidyverse and one of my favorite packages for data manipulation, has a vectorized if function perfect for the occasion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wes Anderson Color Palettes for R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11-08-wes-anderson-movie-color-palettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11-08-wes-anderson-movie-color-palettes/</guid>
      <description>Are you a Wes Anderson fan and regular R user? If you want a color scheme makeover for your R visualizations, check out this fun Wes Anderson color palette package by Karthik Ram. Great stuff&amp;hellip; I just tried out The Grand Budapest Hotel palette for a correlation matrix (see above)!
Source: Karthik&amp;rsquo;s Wes Anderson project (on GitHub)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Visualizations via R &#43; iGraph</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11-06-network-visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11-06-network-visualizations/</guid>
      <description>Network visualizations can be useful for understanding entity and large data interdependencies. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using R and the iGraph package to explore network analysis and found this tutorial to be EXCELLENT by Katherine Ognyanova. It takes a lot of time to build these network graphs and more time to interpret, but definitely rewarding when it provides insights you may have otherwise overlooked. The screenshot above is a network diagram that I made to represent Amazon product copurchases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K-Means Clustering</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-09-23-unsupervised-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-09-23-unsupervised-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>First quarter of grad school is finally over! Now with some free time, I finally learned Git (for BASH emulation), set up a GitHub account, and looking forward to collaborating on analytics projects. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in R or machine learning, one of my projects is a basic ML exercise that relies on the k-means algorithm for clustering.
Source: Unsupervised Machine Learning via k-means Algorithm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning R with swirl</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-08-20-learning-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-08-20-learning-r/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel&amp;rsquo;s pivot tables and Google Maps&amp;hellip; Obvious differences here, but both are driven by split-apply-combine methodologies that visualize data sets. If you want to learn how to make a pivot table &amp;ldquo;from scratch,&amp;rdquo; or enhance your analytics capabilities beyond Excel, learn R (or Python) as a starting point. R is an analytics and graphics programming language that is free, fun, and an interactive way to learn the R basics is via swirl.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>