<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Javier&#39;s Data Site</title>
    <link>/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Javier&#39;s Data Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>March Madness Predictive Modeling Competition</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-03-13-march-madness-prediction-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-03-13-march-madness-prediction-competition/</guid>
      <description>The UCI Merage Analytics Association is hosting a March Madness prediction competition event on April 4th, come join us! Everybody is invited and we&amp;rsquo;ll be giving prizes to the best forecasters and bracket-pickers. Scan one (or both) of the QR codes in the flyer below or let me know if you have any questions. Hope to see you there!
Source: March Madness Event at UCI&amp;rsquo;s Paul Merage School of Business</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Event (Super Bowl Predictive Modeling)</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-01-29-analytics-speaking-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-01-29-analytics-speaking-event/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago, I knew nothing about the NFL (despite my passion for fútbol!). I teamed up with my classmate and knowledgeable NFL fan, Kaitlyn Drake, and developed a model and game simulation via R to predict the Super Bowl winner and final scores. We predicted the Rams winning 15-14… it’ll be a close game. We relied on Poisson regression, game simulation, and C4.5 / J48 decision tree to derive our results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python for Business FREE In-Person Training</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-01-10-python-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-01-10-python-for-business/</guid>
      <description>Interested in an instructor led Python crash course? I&amp;rsquo;m a board member for UCI&amp;rsquo;s Merage Analytics Club and we&amp;rsquo;re hosting a 1.5 hour Python for Business training led by my classmate and extremely talented programmer and data storyteller, Samira Kumar Varadharajan.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be walking through Jupyter Notebook and providing an introduction to the following: 1. Basic Python libraries 2. Better visualizations in Python 3. Machine learning via Scikit-Learn
This event is open to all (students and non-students), is free for MSA members, and only costs 5 bucks for nonmembers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Machine Learning by Hand</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-26-really-learning-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-26-really-learning-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning via R, Python, (enter your tool of choice here)&amp;hellip; Not bad. But doing machine learning by hand, wow&amp;hellip; This is a true study of patience!
For a school assignment, we had to deconstruct a supervised machine learning model (Naive Bayes) using one data set for training and another for testing, all by hand. This was definitely rewarding being able to understand the depth of conditional probabilities in this classifier model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Music Production</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-08-machine-learning-for-music-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-08-machine-learning-for-music-production/</guid>
      <description>If you know me personally, you likely know I enjoy playing with analog / digital synthesizers and experimental music production. I love seeing my interests cross&amp;hellip; FactorSynth, a new virtual musical tool and Ableton Live plug-in, uses machine learning to decompose your audio clips into elements. These musical elements can then be modified and recombined in various ways (in real-time). Check out this demo reel (my words don&amp;rsquo;t do this new device justice)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Azure&#39;s AI Capabilities</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10-01-microsoft-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10-01-microsoft-azure/</guid>
      <description>Building and training ML models takes a ton of time. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Azure can now automate several steps in your AI development process including &amp;ldquo;data transformation, model selection and hyperparameter tuning.&amp;rdquo; Really impressed that Azure is making this tech more accessible and easier to use. If you have hands-on work experience with Azure and don&amp;rsquo;t mind me asking you some questions, please message me, thanks!
Source: Microsoft Announcement: Automated AI via Azure</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K-Means Clustering</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-09-23-unsupervised-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-09-23-unsupervised-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>First quarter of grad school is finally over! Now with some free time, I finally learned Git (for BASH emulation), set up a GitHub account, and looking forward to collaborating on analytics projects. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in R or machine learning, one of my projects is a basic ML exercise that relies on the k-means algorithm for clustering.
Source: Unsupervised Machine Learning via k-means Algorithm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix&#39;s Machine Learning Infrastructure</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-08-28-netflix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-08-28-netflix/</guid>
      <description>Netflix uses R and Python for machine learning and predictive modeling to support content recommendations and FAST delivery of content. On the We Are Netflix podcast series, Netflix has done an amazing job interviewing their data scientists and explaining how machine learning is enhancing the Netflix experience.
Source: WeAreNetflix on YouTube</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>