<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scatter podcast on Javier Orraca. Data Scientist.</title>
    <link>/scatterpodcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scatter podcast on Javier Orraca. Data Scientist.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 12:21:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/scatterpodcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 22 w/ UPenn</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/episode-022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/episode-022/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 022 of Scatter Podcast,I had an engaging interview with Will Chase, Data Scientist at the University of Pennsylvania. I stumbled upon one of Will&amp;rsquo;s interactive, web-based data visualizations (&amp;ldquo;Visualizing Risk: Remotely Triggered Earthquakes&amp;rdquo; - link below) and was fascinated by the way he leveraged the power of R, Mapbox, and D3 for this stunning data storytelling project.
Will has a BS in Microbiology and is almost entirely self-taught in the programming, data science, and advanced visualization space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 21 w/ Zeff.ai</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/episode-021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/episode-021/</guid>
      <description>For Episode 021 of Scatter Podcast, I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to have had the chance to interview Ben Taylor! Ben, the Co-Founder and Chief AI Officer at Zeff, is a wealth of knowledge about data science, artificial intelligence, and careers in these fields. I had a great time with him and we cover a lot including one of Ben&amp;rsquo;s recent, jaw-dropping side projects that is in development: A trained, AI-powered Call of Duty player that battles humans over Xbox Live!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 20 w/ MaCher</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-09-02-scatter-podcast-episode-020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-09-02-scatter-podcast-episode-020/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 020 of Scatter Podcast, I had a lot of fun hosting industrial designer Ben Denzinger, Product Designer at MaCher. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a traditional data science episode but one focused on a topic that analytics and data science teams should become familiar with: Design Thinking. Design thinking is not a new concept, product designers like Ben have used it for decades, yet it is a framework that can be used in almost all aspects of business to justify your existing solution or to develop alternative solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 19 w/ Amazon</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-08-19-scatter-podcast-episode-019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 03:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-08-19-scatter-podcast-episode-019/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 019 of Scatter Podcast, I discuss data science at Amazon with John Peach, Sr. Data Scientist. John has an extensive data science background ranging from academia, to early-stage startups, to large data drive organizations such as Amazon. His team helps to improve and expand the capabilities of Alexa Skills (third party applications).
John actively participates in his local data science community, he is one of the leaders of the Orange County R Users Group (&amp;ldquo;OCRUG&amp;rdquo;), and he frequently speaks at data science conferences around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 18 w/ Saatchi &amp; Saatchi</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-08-12-scatter-podcast-episode-018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-08-12-scatter-podcast-episode-018/</guid>
      <description>Lots of neat things happening at the intersection of media &amp;amp; entertainment, analytics, and operations. For Episode 018 of Scatter Podcast, I interviewed Leondra R. James, Manager, Analytics &amp;amp; Operations at Saatchi &amp;amp; Saatchi.
From violinist and music major to data scientist, Leondra has had a unique mix of academic and professional experiences that shaped her career in data. Saatchi &amp;amp; Saatchi is a global advertising agency operating in 76 countries and Leondra works in their Los Angeles office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 17 w/ ViralGains</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-29-scatter-podcast-episode-017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-29-scatter-podcast-episode-017/</guid>
      <description>For Episode 017 of Scatter Podcast, I interviewed Justin Fortier, Principal Data Scientist at ViralGains. Justin and I met at the Data Science GO conference in 2018 and I enjoyed getting to learn about his journey as a data scientist. ViralGains is a video advertising technology startup that helps publishers push video ad content to the most appropriate consumers. Given that ViralGains operates within the real-time bidding (&amp;ldquo;RTB&amp;rdquo;) domain, their ad bidding and classification algorithms need to transact and process within 100 milliseconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 16 w/ MeridianLink</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-22-scatter-podcast-episode-016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-22-scatter-podcast-episode-016/</guid>
      <description>For Episode 016 of Scatter Podcast, I had a great time interviewing Ben Lewis, Business Intelligence Analyst at MeridianLink. Ben and I met at a hackathon hosted by the Orange County R Users Group (&amp;ldquo;OCRUG&amp;rdquo;) and I was immediately impressed by his R skills. He has an Industrial Engineering and Operations Research background from the University of California, Berkeley, and as a BI Analyst at MeridianLink, he regularly programs in R for analytics, dashboards, and Shiny web-apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 15 w/ General Motors</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-15-scatter-podcast-episode-015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-15-scatter-podcast-episode-015/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 015 of Scatter Podcast, I had the pleasure of interviewing Meltem Ballan, Ph.D., Data Scientist and Architect at General Motors. Meltem&amp;rsquo;s deep analytical and data science expertise developed over her 20 years of experience in academia, consulting, and the corporate world. In fact, before &amp;ldquo;data science&amp;rdquo; became a catchphrase, Meltem was referred to as an algorithm developer.
At GM, Meltem&amp;rsquo;s team aims to enhance the driver experience where she applies neuroscience theory to analyze massive data sets via machine learning and artificial intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 14 w/ Fehr &amp; Peers</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-08-scatter-podcast-episode-014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-07-08-scatter-podcast-episode-014/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 014 of Scatter Podcast, I interview David Wasserman, AICP, Transportation Planner &amp;amp; Data Scientist at Fehr &amp;amp; Peers. Specializing in transportation planning and engineering services, Fehr &amp;amp; Peers is a consulting firm that has serviced public and private sectors since 1985. David has worked with them for four years at the intersection of data science, transportation and urban planning, and he takes us through a deep dive into some of the work that he&amp;rsquo;s done (providing career tips along the way!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 13 w/ Method Data Science</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-06-03-scatter-podcast-episode-013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-06-03-scatter-podcast-episode-013/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 013 of Scatter Podcast, I had a great time interviewing Beau Walker, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of Method Data Science. Beau is actively involved in the data science community, is a passionate R and Python educator, and it was a pleasure to glean some career insights from him. Method is on a mission to inspire and train the next generation of data scientists, and they&amp;rsquo;re accomplishing this by managing small teams of Resident Data Scientists working on real-world data engagements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 12 w/ TBWA-Chiat-Day</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-27-scatter-podcast-episode-012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-27-scatter-podcast-episode-012/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 012 of Scatter Podcast, I interview Matt Segal, Data Director at TBWA/Chiat/Day, a global creative advertising agency. Chiat/Day gained global notoriety with their &amp;ldquo;1984&amp;rdquo; ad campaign for Apple introducing the Macintosh computer. Their forward-thinking and disruptive style make for a unique place to work as a data strategist, and Matt discusses the benefits of data careers at advertising agencies. Matt shares recent project examples his data team has been involved with, he discusses tools regularly used for social listening and web analytics, and he shares solid resources for those of you interested in this space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 11 w/ CBRE</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-20-scatter-podcast-episode-011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-20-scatter-podcast-episode-011/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 011 of Scatter Podcast, I interview Vince Giovannini, Data Scientist at CBRE, a commercial real estate investment company that also offers a wide range of real estate consulting services. Vince works in the Labor Analytics team at CBRE and shares great insights about the labor products he has worked on and how labor is connected to real estate economics. Vince shares several project examples that he&amp;rsquo;s been a part of at CBRE and it was great getting to hear how his firm uses data science to derive deeper insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 10 w/ FortyFour</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-13-scatter-podcast-episode-010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-13-scatter-podcast-episode-010/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 010 of Scatter Podcast, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to host guest Ryan Anderson, Director of Performance Marketing &amp;amp; Analytics at FortyFour. FortyFour is an independent digital agency based in Atlanta, GA, and Ryan leads their analytics team. Ryan, a Georgia Institute of Technology engineering and MBA alum, was a driving force for me diving into analytics and data science (thank you!).
Ryan has been a great sounding board the past couple of years and he&amp;rsquo;s a wealth of knowledge on analytics and digital strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 9 w/ RealBlocks</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-06-scatter-podcast-episode-009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-05-06-scatter-podcast-episode-009/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 009 of Scatter Podcast, I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to release my interview with Perrin Quarshie, CEO &amp;amp; Founder of RealBlocks. For those of you interested in real estate, technology, investing, blockchain&amp;hellip; This episode is for you!
Built upon the Ethereum blockchain, RealBlocks allows accredited investors to buy into private equity real estate funds through the purchase of digital assets. RealBlocks went through #Techstars NYC&amp;rsquo;s program (one of the top startup accelerators) and recently raised $3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 8 w/ Chegg</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-29-scatter-podcast-episode-008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-29-scatter-podcast-episode-008/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 008 of Scatter Podcast, I interview guest Taranveer Singh and discuss his work as a Data Scientist at Chegg. Through natural language processing (&amp;ldquo;NLP&amp;rdquo;) and data science, Taran&amp;rsquo;s team provides Chegg customers with a better user experience, ensuring the customer voice is heard. Chegg operates fast and smart, and data science enables the business to quickly research and deploy product features that are most desired by their community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 7 w/ NeoGenomics Laboratories</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-22-scatter-podcast-episode-007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-22-scatter-podcast-episode-007/</guid>
      <description>On Episode 007 of Scatter Podcast, I interview guest Nicholas Stavrou and discuss his work as an Associate Scientist in Computational Biology at NeoGenomics Laboratories, a cancer diagnostic and pharma research company. Neo is advancing precision medication and Nicholas and I had an engaging talk about cancer cell classification, neural networks and AI models for cancer research, and how Nicholas developed his skills to land his role at Neo. Nicholas graduated from USC in 2017 and he shares some great tips and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 6 w/ T-Mobile</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-15-scatter-podcast-episode-006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-15-scatter-podcast-episode-006/</guid>
      <description>For the sixth episode of Scatter Podcast, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to introduce Juan Pablo Murillo, Data Scientist at T-Mobile at their U.S. headquarters in Bellevue, WA (greater Seattle area). Mathematics instructor turned data scientist, Juan Pablo is in customer analytics and works with engineering and analytics teams to improve the T-Mobile and MetroPCS customer experience. He has been a solid data science mentor for me over the last few months, reviewing, rating, and critiquing some of my R scripts and insights that I derived&amp;hellip; Sharp guy and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share his data analytics passion with others!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 5 w/ Databricks</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-08-scatter-podcast-episode-005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-04-08-scatter-podcast-episode-005/</guid>
      <description>New episode of Scatter Podcast is online with Rafi Kurlansik of Databricks. Rafi has great perspective given his unique opportunities as a data scientist within tech sales and pre-sales teams. He also shares some great resources if you’re interested in learning Databricks, a cloud-based unified analytics platform. Happy Monday!
Other links: Databricks Databricks Community Edition MLflow on Databricks
Scatter Podcast is available on SoundCloud, iTunes &amp;amp; Apple Podcasts, Spotify, TuneIn, Google Play Music, Stitcher Radio, Castbox, and Podcast Republic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official Launch w/ Episodes 1-4</title>
      <link>/scatterpodcast/2019-03-31-scatter-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scatterpodcast/2019-03-31-scatter-podcast/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to announce that Scatter Podcast is finally live (available on most music and podcast streaming platforms)! The first four episodes include a podcast intro and three episodes with engaging guests from The Home Depot, Pacific Life, and NYC &amp;amp; Company.
I plan to release one episode weekly - Look out for upcoming interviews with data science reps from T-Mobile, Databricks, KPMG, Chegg, Technossus, Levi Strauss, Google, TensorIoT, and more!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>